A Guide to the Ellen Gertrude Tompkins Kidd papers, 1791-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Ellen Gertrude Tompkins Kidd papers, 1791-1998
The Library of Virginia
52005
.9 cu. ft. and 2 boxes
Ellen Gertrude Tompkins Kidd
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ellen Kidd Penick, Richmond, Virginia
Biographical Information
Ellen Gertrude Tompkins was born between 1846 and 1855 in Richmond, Virginia, to Edmund William Tompkins and Julia Moseby Burton Tompkins. She attended the Pegram School for Girls in Richmond. Tompkins began making pickles in 1868 using a family recipe from her great-grandmother, and by 1872, she had established the Pin Money Pickle Company. Also in 1872, she married John Boulware Kidd (1836-1910) on April 4, and they had ten children, five of whom survived to adulthood. Wile the successful Pin Money company continued to grow, Kidd became active in the women's suffrage movement. Ellen Gertrude Tompkins Kidd died 3 February 1932 in Richmond and was buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1791-1998, of Ellen Gertrude Tompkins Kidd (ca. 1846-1932) of Richmond, Virginia, consisting of business records, compositions, correspondence, deeds, insurance policies and records, legal records, money, photographs, poems, receipts, and wills. Papers detail Kidd's Pin-Money Pickle company, her and her family's travels through the United States and Europe, women's suffrage, and Richmond society and culture, as well as the Boulware, Kidd, and Tompkins families. Transcriptions for the collection (excepting money and photographs) are available.Ellen Gertrude Tompkins Kidd papers, 1791-1998. Accession 52005. Personal papers collection, The Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia.
Contents List
- Letters, 1849-1908, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters, 1918-1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Official correspondence, 1900-1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pin-Money Pickles documents (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Suffrage documents, 1920, 1926, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Wills, 1791-1863 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Legal documents and receipts, 1840-1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Insurance records, 1846-1871, (one document located in Oversize Box 14) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Poems and compositions (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous documents and items (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Money--local, state, and Confederate, ca. 1861-1865 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Menus (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings, 1903-1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Transcriptions of the Ellen Gertrude Tompkins Kidd papers, 1791-1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)